Curriculum vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION Muthukumar Pandaram

- Coppistr. 20, 10365 Berlin
- +4915175552738
- pmkumar1308@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/muthukumarpandaram/

A versatile and analytical Master's student in Computational Neuroscience with over 2 years of research experience gained through working at different research labs across the world. Possess a Bachelor's in Mechanical Engineering with demonstrated skills in robotics, analysis of neural data and machine learning. Passionate about working at the intersection of neuroscience, Robotics and Al.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Oct 2020 - Dec 2023 Master of Science - Computational Neuroscience

Technical University of Berlin, Berlin (Germany)

- Deutschlandstipendium (German National Scholarship) recipient for the academic year 2020-21, awarded by BMBF, Germany and a private sponsor.
- Master thesis: Optimisation of the parameter space for deep brain stimulation fiber filtering across neuropsychiatric disorders, Supervisor: Prof. Dr. med. / PhD Andreas Horn, Harvard Medical School
- **GPA:** 1.6

Jul 2014 - Apr 2019 Bachelor of Engineering - Mechanical Engineering

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore (India)

- CGPA: 9.52/10 (Batch Topper and Gold Medallist)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Publications

Empirically identifying and computationally modelling the brain-behaviour relationship for human scene categorization. Karapetian A, Boyanova A, Pandaram M, Obermayer K, Kietzmann TC, Cichy RM. J Cogn Neurosci. 2023 Nov 1;35(11):1879-1897.

Soft tactile sensors with variable compliance. Azim, S., Srinivasan, A., Pandaram, M., Kow, J., De Boer, G., Wang, H., Alazmani, A. and Culmer, P., 2017. In 2017 IEEE SENSORS (pp. 1-3). IEEE.

Lab Rotation Projects

Neural Mechanisms of real world visual categorical decisions, Neural Dynamics of Visual Cognition Lab, FU Berlin, Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Radoslaw Martin Cichy

Context based classification using a bandit modulated feed forward classifier, Sprekeler Lab, TU Berlin, Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Henning Sprekeler

Optimising volume of tissue activated threshold parameter for deep brain stimulation fiber filtering, NetStim Lab, Charité - Universitätsmedizin Berlin, Supervisor: Prof. Dr. med. / PhD Andreas Horn

Relevant Courses taken Machine Intelligence, Models of Higher Brain Function, Acquisition and Analysis of Neural Data

Technical Skills Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, MATLAB

Middleware: ROS

Other: PyTorch, OpenCV, Docker, Git, Linux(Bash), Gazebo, PyBullet

CAD/CAE: PTC Creo, SolidWorks, ANSYS, Abagus

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mar 2024 – July 2024

Senior Software Engineer-Robotics and Al

Surgical Robotics R&D, Meril Healthcare, Chennai (India)

- Developing motion control software for teleoperated robotic surgery.
- Developing 3D reconstruction and segmentation of medical images for pre-operative plan-

Skills acquired: Git, CI/CD, Python, Deep Learning, Linux, ROS, OpenCV, PyTorch

Nov 2022 – Jan 2024 Working Student

Manipulator Cluster, Gestalt Robotics, Berlin (Germany)

Developed a grasping solution for bin picking using open source models like DexNet.

Mar 2021 - Oct 2022 Student Research Assistant

Robotics and Biology Lab, Technical University of Berlin, Berlin (Germany)

- Developed the control hardware for soft robotic hands using proportional valves and flow sensors using ROS as middleware. (Funded by Science of Intelligence excellence cluster)

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Oliver Brock

Nov 2019 - May 2020

Research Intern

Centre for Alternate Cooling Technologies, PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore (India)

- Developed an experimental apparatus for evaluating the performance of a Solar Assisted Liquid Desiccant based air-conditioning system.

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Madhu Ganesh

May 2019 – Aug 2019 Undergraduate Research Intern

Robotics and Manufacturing Automation Lab, McMaster University, Hamilton (Canada)

 Modified a custom written open-source numerical solver in MATLAB and C++ for simulating the hyperelastic behaviour of soft robotic actuators.

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Gary Bone

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019 Research Intern

Medical Mechatronics Lab, National University of Singapore, Singapore (Singapore)

 Interfaced a battery-less NFC based transponder platform to get data from analog sensors developed at the Singapore Institute of Neurotechnology through an Android app.

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Hongliang Ren

May 2018 - Jul 2018 Summer Research Fellow

Manufacturing Engineering Section, Indian Institute of Technology, Madras, Chennai (India)

 Developed an algorithm for automated registration of design surfaces (in NURBS surface format) and the manufactured surfaces for inspection of free form surfaces.

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Samuel G.L

May 2017 - Jul 2017 Research Intern

Surgical Technologies lab, University of Leeds, Leeds (United Kingdom)

 Developed a finite element model in ABAQUS to simulate the hyperelastic behaviour of a soft tactile sensor body and compared the different hyperelastic models.

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Peter Culmer and Prof. Dr. Ali Alazmani